<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spring on # sudo init 5 - beta</title>
    <link>https://www.sudoinit5.com/categories/spring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spring on # sudo init 5 - beta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.sudoinit5.com/categories/spring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Reactive Cloud Apps with SpringBoot</title>
      <link>https://www.sudoinit5.com/post/spring-boot-testing-producer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sudoinit5.com/post/spring-boot-testing-producer/</guid>
      <description>The Producer Environment In the world of testing, we dont need much inspiration to get the job done. However, when it comes to what to use, you may be left wandering whether you&amp;rsquo;ll hit all of the right frameworks and tools to validate your business code. Also likely, you&amp;rsquo;ll also need to figure out how to cross validate a producer app with a consumer app(s) that you may not even own!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Authorization with Reactive Spring Security 5</title>
      <link>https://www.sudoinit5.com/post/spring-reactive-authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sudoinit5.com/post/spring-reactive-authorization/</guid>
      <description>Configuring Authorization against a Webflux App Effective security can insulate our applications from ill effects of malicious, and accidental intent in many aspects of programming. Things like network security can only go so far in isolating harm to distributed computing applications. Prevent malicious hackers from gaining access to your systems by ensuring the tools meet the standards for your appcation.
Spring Security WebFlux is the framework that lets us declare security constructs to our ordinary WebFluxapplications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactive Websocket Client with Spring</title>
      <link>https://www.sudoinit5.com/post/spring-reactive-ws-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sudoinit5.com/post/spring-reactive-ws-client/</guid>
      <description>This Demo This demo client will connect and receive events from any URL that emits an open websocket stream. We have an existing server to stand up that can supply the socket events. A reactive client means that we can respond to backpressure, and weild the Observer pattern to our client connections.
The Client (SANS web) We can use our favorite Spring Application Initializr start dot spring dot io to generate the application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Zipkin Tracing with Spring Boot</title>
      <link>https://www.sudoinit5.com/post/spring-tracing-zipkin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sudoinit5.com/post/spring-tracing-zipkin/</guid>
      <description>Tracing Motivation The more distributed a system the harder it is to debug errors, find latency, and to understand the potentially cascading impact of a bug. External monitoring only tells you the overall response time and number of invocations but doesn’t give us a way to understand internal invocations. Structured log entries can be correllated, eventually, to paint a picture of the movement of a request through a system, but structured logs are not easy to query.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sending and consuming messages with Spring and KafKa</title>
      <link>https://www.sudoinit5.com/post/spring-kafka/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sudoinit5.com/post/spring-kafka/</guid>
      <description>Spring Kafka Writer and Readers What is Kafka Apache Kafka is an open-source stream-processing software platform developed by the Apache Software Foundation written in Scala and Java. You&amp;rsquo;ll find more information about Kafka at it&amp;rsquo;s Homepage.
Intro to Spring For Apache Kafka The Spring for Apache Kafka (spring-kafka) project applies core Spring concepts to the development of Kafka-based messaging solutions. It provides a &amp;ldquo;template&amp;rdquo; as a high-level abstraction for sending messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Test Slices</title>
      <link>https://www.sudoinit5.com/post/spring-test-slices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sudoinit5.com/post/spring-test-slices/</guid>
      <description>Spring Test Slices Simplify testing by isolating the logical layers above and below that thing under test. These are the invariants. In a Spring Boot application, autoconfiguration produces a large monolithic application context.
Test slices allow us to segment the application context in terms of logical layers. As an example, the @WebMvcTest slice only includes components related to the web tier, like @Controller-annotated components.
The Basic Test As an example, let&amp;rsquo;s look at the structure of a unit test that looks something like the default unit test generated by the Spring Initializr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>