<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on # sudo init 5 - beta</title>
    <link>https://www.sudoinit5.com/categories/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on # sudo init 5 - beta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.sudoinit5.com/categories/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup and Customize a Login Page With Reactive Spring Security.</title>
      <link>https://www.sudoinit5.com/post/spring-reactive-auth-forms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sudoinit5.com/post/spring-reactive-auth-forms/</guid>
      <description>Customized WebFlux Form Authentication This demonstration examines Spring Security WebFlux&amp;rsquo;s Authentication mechanisms. We will look at authentication with HTML forms using Mustache, User Authentication, and customized form-based login / logout configurations.
The ServerHttpSecurity Configuration SecurityWebFilterChain is the governing chain of [WebFilter]&amp;rsquo;s that allows us to lock down reactive WebFlux applications. With @EnableWebFluxSecurity turned on, we can build this object by issuing commands to the ServerHttpSecurity DSL object.
SecurityConfiguration.java:
@EnableWebFluxSecurity @Slf4j @Configuration public class SecurityConfiguration { @Bean public SecurityWebFilterChain securityWebFilterChain(ServerHttpSecurity http) { return http .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup and customize Authentication against a WebFlux Application</title>
      <link>https://www.sudoinit5.com/post/spring-reactive-auth-basic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sudoinit5.com/post/spring-reactive-auth-basic/</guid>
      <description>Configuring Authentication against a WebFlux app This demonstration examines Spring Security WebFlux&amp;rsquo;s Authentication mechanisms. We will look at Authentication request escalation, as well as user-domain customizations.
Authentication flow-control How do we determine when a request must provide an authentication context? Spring does this with help from an AuthenticationEntryPoint that identifies un-authenticated requests and returns with a response to the user to perform some authentication action.
Configure ServerHttpSecurity to use HTTP-BASIC by calling it&amp;rsquo;s httpBasic() method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Authorization with Reactive Spring Security 5</title>
      <link>https://www.sudoinit5.com/post/spring-reactive-authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sudoinit5.com/post/spring-reactive-authorization/</guid>
      <description>Configuring Authorization against a Webflux App Effective security can insulate our applications from ill effects of malicious, and accidental intent in many aspects of programming. Things like network security can only go so far in isolating harm to distributed computing applications. Prevent malicious hackers from gaining access to your systems by ensuring the tools meet the standards for your appcation.
Spring Security WebFlux is the framework that lets us declare security constructs to our ordinary WebFluxapplications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>